# **ULUKBEK** NUSUBALIEV

- nusubaliev.dev@gmail.com
- **(**773)-982-9270
- ♥ Chicago IL
- in ulukbek-nusubaliev
- ♠ Luka7711

# **>** summary

Fullstack developer with 3+ years of experience in the retail industry. Specializes in JavaScript, React, and Python, also working well with AWS services. Highly experienced in all aspects of the software development lifecycle, from concept to development and delivery. Greatly performs under pressure and in a fast-paced working environment. Demonstrates commitment, hard work, and willingness to learn.

## > skills

### **LANGUAGES**

Python

**JavaScript** 

Ruby

#### **AWS**

Lex

Lambda

Step Function

Api Gateway

Dynamo

Cloud Formation

IAM

Cloud Watch

Secret Manager

### FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES

React

Node JS

jQuery

# **DATABASE**

PostgresSQL

Mongo

Dynamo

### **OTHER**

Git

Github

**NPM** 

API

# **>** employment

# **Thrasio**

Frontend developer

- Developed and designed React components.
- Resolved problematic patterns in CSS by applying Linter rules.
- Closely collaborated with the team to integrate client-side APIs.
- Improved software functionality by creating automation tests utilizing Selenium.

Tech Stack: React JS, CSS, Selenium.

Chicago IL 11/2021 to 07/2022

Chicago IL

07/2022 to 10/2022

## AWS developer

· Worked on an Agile Development team to build a conversational interface for the Slack application.

- Designed AWS Cloud Formation templates to build and deploy AWS services.
- Developed custom NoSQL database usage for organizing, and maintaining API data.
- Improved speed and latency of chatbot interaction by analyzing Cloud Watch metrics and logs.
- Wrote unit and integration tests to ensure 100% of the code was without bugs.

Tech Stack: Python, AWS LEX, AWS Lambda, API Gateway, Step Functions, DynamoDB, Pytest.

# **Professional Freelancer**

Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan 05/2020 to 10/2021

# Full Stack Developer

- Maintained, developed, and designed an e-commerce website for small businesses.
- Designed and tested **RESTful** APIs using **Express JS and Postman**.
- Implemented stable and maintainable codebases using React.
- Improved CSS layouts using grid and flexbox techniques.

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, Javascript, React JS, Node, Express, Mongo DB.

# Kids in Danger

Chicago IL

12/2019 to 05/2020

# Front End Developer (volunteer)

- · Developed google chrome extension for the Amazon platform that informs buyers about hazardous children's products using React.
- Communicated with the product owner and project manager on the improvements, integration, and further enhancements in software.
- Wrote application-level code to interact with APIs and Web Services using Ajax and JSON.
- Improved UX/UI by redesigning React components.
- Delivered and presented the software product ahead of planning time.

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, React JS, AJAX.

# General Assembly

Chicago IL

03/2019 to 07/2019

# **Full Stack Developer**

- Developed 4+ projects starting from planning, and drawing wireframes to fully functional and testable full-stack applications.
- · Worked closely with peers to determine problems, and testing methods using Mocha and Chai.
- Built SQL and NoSQL databases using PostgreSQL and MongoDB.
- Deployed application to the web via cloud-based hosting Heroku.

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, React, Ruby, Node, Express, MongoDB, PostgresSQL.

# **>** education

Web Development Bootcamp - General Assembly

03/2019 to 07/2019

Full-Time Immersive - Software Engineering

Kyrgyz Economic University, Kyrgyz Republic Bachelor's Degree in Finance and Financial Management Services. 09/2010 to 07/2016